The strongest model available to you may not fit
on the phone in your hand.
But exposing a personal Mac as a generic remote-execution server
would be unsafe. NearBridge takes a narrower path.
It is a native iPhone and Mac experiment for reaching one explicitly
selected capability on a nearby computer.
Both apps are user-launched. They advertise locally,
but a discovered device remains untrusted.
The user compares the same six-digit code
and approves it on both sides.
NearBridge binds a fresh authenticated session to the paired keys.
Discovery never becomes authentication by itself.
The iPhone requests contact with the Mac’s Primary Holon.
The signed workflow confirms one registered inert-text capability.
The Mac Host—not the remote question—chooses
which adapter can execute it.
I ask one ordinary, non-sensitive question.
It is signed, expiring, session-correlated, and input-bounded.
The Mac routes it to the selected OpenAI GPT-5.6 Sol
model-only adapter.
The separate app-sandboxed XPC request uses the Responses API
with store false, omits tools, and has no file, shell, workspace,
Git, or device control.
The Mac signs the typed result. The iPhone validates sender,
session, expiry, signature, and correlation.
Only then does it display the answer.
Both sides retain the same execution receipt.
The receipt records provider, capability, outcome,
acknowledgement, integrity, and latency.
Sanitized diagnostics omit prompt and answer bodies
and redact credential-shaped values.
This is a bounded personal-AI bridge—not arbitrary remote execution,
payload encryption, or a production-readiness claim.
Codex turned the security brief into incremental checkpoints,
native flows, isolated runners, and fifty-four tests.
NearBridge lets your phone reach a stronger nearby model
while the Host keeps control and audit.