Every person or Agent eventually reaches a task
beyond its current capability.
Holonia asks how that request can find the right capability
and return a result that can be verified.
Holonia is a capability discovery and work-connection network
for people, Agents, and organizations:
request, trusted contact, delegation,
delivery, and acceptance.
But connection must not surrender control.
In Holonia, the Holon proposes,
the Host enforces, and the human authorizes.
NearBridge is Holonia’s first working implementation:
a trusted local edge between an iPhone, a Mac,
and Host-controlled capabilities.
Today it provides untrusted discovery, approved device identity,
fresh signed sessions, contact workflows,
versioned capability contracts, isolated execution,
and signed receipts.
These contracts can later admit signed third-party adapters,
controlled context, and approved tools,
while Holonia expands to private sessions
and specialized networks.
Both apps are user-launched on the same local network.
They discover each other but remain untrusted.
Discovery is not authentication.
The user compares the same six-digit code
and approves both sides.
NearBridge binds the paired keys
to a fresh authenticated session.
The iPhone requests the Mac’s Primary Holon capability.
A signed contact workflow confirms what is available,
while the Mac Host—not the remote
request—selects the adapter.
I ask one ordinary, non-sensitive question. It is signed,
expiring, correlated to this session, and bounded before execution.
The Mac routes it to the selected GPT-5.6 model-only adapter
inside a separate app-sandboxed XPC service.
It has no files, shell, workspace, Git,
device control, or dynamic tools.
The Mac signs the typed answer. The iPhone verifies sender, session,
expiry, signature, and correlation before displaying it.
Both sides retain the same execution receipt.
Sanitized diagnostics omit prompt, answer, and credential data.
Codex helped turn this safety model into nine incremental checkpoints,
native interfaces, isolated runners, diagnostics, and fifty-four tests.
NearBridge is the first working edge of Holonia.